Wenqian Zhang

Email: 2194510944@stu.xjtu.edu.cn

Tel: +086 13572223285

Add: No.28, West Xianning Road, Xi'an, Shaanxi, 710049,

P.R. China

Research Interest

- Natural Language Processing
- Computer Vision
- Graph Neural Networks
- Deep Learning
- Machine learning algorithm

I have spent effort on deep learning study and research, particularly on pre-trained language models, graph neural networks, and knowledge graphs. Realizing it is impossible to achieve AGI by focusing on one area, I long for learning knowledge not limited to NLP.

Education Background

Xi'an Jiaotong University, majoring in Computer Science and Technology

2019 - Present

Overall GPA: 83

Related Courses (selected):

Fundamental of optimization, Data Structure and Algorithms, Probability Theory and Stochastic Process, Discrete Mathematical Structures, Programming Fundamentals, Foundation of Life science.

English:

- CET (College English Test) Band 4: 588
- CET (College English Test) Band 6: 545
- IELTS: 7 (R 8 / L 7.5 / S 6 /W 6)

Publication

- KCD: Knowledge Walks and Textual Cues Enhanced Political Perspective Detection in News Media Wenqian Zhang*, Shangbin Feng*, Zilong Chen*, Zhenyu Lei, Jundong Li, Minnan Luo Accepted at NAACL 2022 main conference
- Knowledge Graph Augmented Political Perspective Detection in News Media Shangbin Feng*, Zilong Chen*, Wenqian Zhang*, Qingyao Li, Qinghua Zheng, Xiaojun Chang, Minnan Luo Arxiv 2021: https://arxiv.org/abs/2108.03861

Research Experience

Member of LUD (Luo lab Undergraduate Division), Xi'an Jiaotong University

9.2021 - Present

- Study graph and knowledge implement in NLP.
- Study graph and external knowledge enhanced stance detection.
- Study solving spoiler detection with graph neutral network and knowledge graph.

NUS Summer Workshop (Topic: Artificial Intelligence of Things), Co-leader of the group 5.2021 - 7.2021



- Won a third price of Artificial Intelligence of Things by Design a Smart home Air condition Control System
- (ranking 5/19 among all world workshop teams in 2021)
- Realize communication between Raspberry Pi and PC, Code backend of control system by Python
- Use Linear regression to generate PMV model

Circuit calculator designed by MATLAB

9.2020 - 12.2020

- Calculate circuit via node-voltage analysis
- Simplify circuit via Thevenin's theorem
- Analyze dynamic circuit and plot transient response

My notepad designed by JAVA, Co-leader of the group

3.2021 - 4.2021

- Design main frame work
- Realize picture insert and adjustment

Extracurricular Activities

Golden Autumn English corner, Volunteer

11.2019

Yixing Racing Team, Member of Frame department.

11.2019 - 9.2020

- Participate in designing car frame with Solidworks and Catia
- Participate welding frame

Zhongyin Academic counseling Association, Secretary

9.2020 - 2021.10

- Edit Engineering drawing brochure and Circuits brochure
- Participate in Q&A

Aid education for Renhe high school online

8.2020

Zhongyin Basketball team

9.2019 - 6.2021

Honors and Awards

Honorable Mention in Mathematical Contest in Modeling

2021

2019-2020 academic year Third-Class scholarship

2020

First prize at the provincial level of Contemporary Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling

2020

Honored volunteer of Golden Autumn English corner

2019

Family Members

- Father, Baolin Zhang: professor in College of Materials Science and Engineering, Guilin University of Technology. My father is working on Memristors that can be used as the basic elements of neuromorphic circuits.
- Mother, Jihong Li: associate professor in College of Arts, Guilin University of Technology
- Sister, Tianchan Ren: Ph.D. student in Law School, Peking University
- Sister, Tianpei Ren: Ph.D. student in School of Public Policy & Management, Tsinghua University
 My family is always keen on reading and exchanging opinions, strongly supports me to raise questions and
 to do research, and offers me instructions and patience to discover something meaningful.

Others

I like playing basketball and participate in college basketball team. In holidays, I enjoy travelling and have driven to Qinghai Lake, Hukou waterfall of Yellow River. In Sept of 2017, with my family I travelled to CMU, Pittsburg University, Cornell University and New York University.